♦770 Canyon Road Providence UT, 84332♦ (417) 399-3171 ♦joshua.smith4@aggiemail.usu.edu♦

I am an ambitious bilingual student currently studying Electrical Engineering with minors in Computer Science and Mathematics at USU. I have excellent analytical, mathematical, logic and interpersonal skills. I have a passion for computer science and problem solving and love to learn and extrapolate ideas from data. I feel that, with my skills and qualifications, I will be a great asset to the Space Dynamics Laboratory team, bringing professional and precise work as well as experience in teaching and teamwork.

Qualifications

I am currently studying to be an computer engineer with a minor in computer science. As seen on my university transcript, I have completed Multivariable Calculus, Linear Algebra, Physics for Scientists and Engineers II, Computer Science I (C++), Computer Science II (C++), and Introduction to Graphical User Interface in Java, and am enrolled now in various relevant classes including Numerical Methods, Computer Science III (C++), Web Development (HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Node.js, Express, etc), and Ordinary Differential Equations. I have knowledge of computer languages (in order of proficiency): C/C++, JavaScript, Java, Python. This is the URL of a github repository where some personal coding projects are held: https://github.com/joshua-smith4/. I invite you to take a look at the code. On a two year mission as an official representative of the LDS Church, I received training and experience in data analysis and organization dynamics. I was able to create a program that successfully automatized the process of ordering and distributing necessary materials using Visual Basic for Applications. I am hard working, a quick learner, and function well in high-pressure situations.

Education

Bachelor in Electrical Engineering/Minor:Computer Science

Current GPA 3.83, Utah State University 2012-Present

High School Diploma, Mountain Crest High School, Hyrum, UT, 2008-2012,

Graduated with academic honors

Work Experience

Space Dynamics Laboratory, Software Developer, Logan, UT 2016-Now

Create automatic tests and testing infrastructures in software for a program called Vantage.

Zortrax USA, Quality Assurance Technician, Logan, UT 2015-2016

Carried out quality assurance checks on 3D Printers, preparing them for customer satisfaction and perfect operation.

Colombia Bogota South Mission, Official Representative, 2013-2015

Lived among and taught native Spanish speaking people. Became fluent in the spoken and written Spanish language. Received medical Spanish experience while serving as health secretary.

Harman Professional Incorporated, Quality Assurance Technician, Sandy, UT 2013

Performed quality assurance checks on technology and products in development, expanding my abilities in precise and accurate work as well as team working skills.

Cache County School District, Tutor of Mathematics, Hyrum, UT 2011-2012

Due to high excellence and aptitudes for math, I was asked to serve as a tutor of mathematics, helping a variety of students at very different levels to understand and apply mathematic principles.

References

Upon request